Jonathan Kurinsky

Philadelphia-based Full-stack SWE

krnsk0.dev | github.com/krnsk0 | linkedin.com/in/krnsk0/

jkurinsky@gmail.com | (847) 962-3309

TECHNOLOGIES

Proficient: Web app development utilizing Node on the back end and React on the front end; single-page app design using state-management frameworks and concepts (Redux, Sagas, React hooks). Highly proficient at ES6+ Javascript; familiar with best practices for functional-light, declarative programming style using libraries like Lodash. Extensive experience with NPM- and webpack-based tooling environment and TDD using Jest, RTL, Enzyme. Specialtizations in web performance, frontend tooling, and frontend architecture. Skilled presenter, speaker, educator. **Some familiarity:** Python; JAMstack; Gatsby; GraphQL; AWS, GCP.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, (August 2020 - Present)

IKEA, Conshohocken: Teach lead for cross-functional squad focusing on web performance and SEO research. Designed and built prototypes and ran A/B tests aimed at discovering performance improvements for IKEA's microfrontends-based global retail platform.

Engineer 2, Software Development (October 2019 - July 2020)

Comcast, Philadelphia: Lead UI dev for greenfield React-based customer-facing payment and ecommerce application with millions of users, part of a part of a multi-year project to unify and simplify experiences for customers and agents accross Comcast web properties.

70/30 split between code and management/education. Co-designed a bespoke React-based microfrontends architecture and built out associated tooling, later rolled out to multiple teams; co-led effort to push cross-functional agile teams toward CI/CD and devops practices. Built and iterated on Node-based microservices. Organized and presented at internal training sessions on JS, React, and Node as part of department-wide effort to unify department around a Node-based stack. Wrote documentation and designed curricula to help onboard junior engineers.

Teaching Fellow (June 2019 - September 2019)

Fullstack Academy, Chicago: Mentored & taught students at 13-week web development bootcamp; wrote a repository using test-based learning to teach direct DOM manipulation; project-managed six student projects; graded & code-reviewed student projects; led algorithm exercises with classes of 20 students; conducted technical interviews with prospective students.

Logistics & Operations Manager (September 2011 - November 2018)

Haymarket Books, Chicago: Self-taught Python to build tools for automating operations workflows for a nonprofit publisher through period of 400% growth in order volume. Solo author & maintainer of a large object-oriented codebase integrating web scrapers, partner APIs, shipping hardware, and data viz tools behind a CLI.

PROJECTS (see portfolio for much more: www.krnsk0.dev)

guser [npm] [repo] August 2020

Open-source interactive git user switcher for the command line.

Pixalive [deployed site] [repo] May 2019

A multi-user, real-time, React-based editor for animated sprites and pixel art built in two weeks. Backed by socket.io-based Node server. (Bootcamp project.)

EDUCATION

Fullstack Academy (January 2019 - May 2019)

13-week rigorous immersive development bootcamp teaching industry-standard professional practices and tooling for modern front- and back-end web development using a Javascript-based stack.

University of Chicago (September 2005 - June 2009)

Bachelor of Arts in philosophy, honors track; focus on mathematical logic & formal semantics. Department awards for academic papers & contributions to undergraduate academic life.